# Ashraf Ali

# Software Engineer

03128915303 | <u>ashraf.uok@hotmail.com</u> |

Lyari, Karachi | <a href="http://ali-ework.github.io">http://ali-ework.github.io</a>



### Summary

Dedicated professional, hardworking individual and highly self-motivated 2.5 years of experience in mobile application development using native platform (Android & iOS) and cross platform (Ionic & React Native), and Full Stack development using .Net(C#). Known good for teamwork and problem solving.

### Software Projects Highlight

#### Kennu Wallet

- > It's your wallet in your smartphone. you can make a purchase at your favorite retail outlet, shop online, request and share money with friends, pay utility bills from home and more. No need to worry about carrying cash or your wallet anymore.
- ➤ Responsible for developing client side using Ionic3/Typescript, and server side using .Net (C#).

#### Bill Payment System.

- > It's .Net based web service that provide single interface to client side application for accessing various Utility Billing, Mobile & International Vouchers, and Mobile Top-up Services.
- Integrate Nadra, Bank Al Habib service for Utility Bill Payment.
- Integrate 1Link service for Mobile Top-up.
- Integrate Nadra Telco's service for Mobile Telco Vouchers.
- Integrate Monami Vouchers service for International Vouchers

#### Askari Mobile Banking

- > User-friendly mobile app allows you to access your Askari bank account(s) anytime, anywhere.
- > Added new feature of Card less cash withdrawals, International Vouchers, Insurance payment.

### MeatMart Shop

> Retails Payment based on cash on delivery to track inventory, sales and generating reports & receipt, developed using native android platform and Firebase as real-time database.

### Tarweed Quran (In Progress)

- Special Word By Word Quran Recitation, great for learning tajweed & reading.
- Click on any word or verse to hear the proper recitation.
- > Repeat each word, verse, & selection many times, place pauses between verses.
- Quran Translation in English and other languages.

### Experience

### Wemsol Pvt.Ltd, Karachi

Feb2016-Apr2016

Android & iOS Intern

- > Designed, developed, and tested Android and iOS applications
- Responsible for rapid prototyping and development of mobile applications

#### Wemsol Pvt.Ltd, Karachi

May 2016-Present

Software Engineer

- > Responsible for developing frontend and backend of mobile application.
- > Add new features to existing mobile application as per client requirement.
- Integrating web services into the existing system.
- > Developing web services from scratch using .Net framework C#
- Work closely with senior engineer, designer and producer.
- Work effectively both independently and part of team with minimal supervision.
- Supervise junior developer and intern on Web and Mobile Application development.

### Additional Experience

Up Work Jun2017-Sep2017

Freelance Developer

- Work on Chatting application developed on Ionic3 using Firebase as database and implement Geofencing feature to allow group chatting in particular range.
- Do reverse engineering work on android applications to find out is either application is storing persistence identifier, silent location tracking and sensitive user profile information

Education	
University of Karachi, Karachi, Bachelor of Software Engineer Grade 'B', CGPA '3.07'	2012-2015
Saint Patrick's College, Karachi, HSC (Pre-Engineer) Grade 'A', Percentage '70'	2009-2010
Bright Public School, Karachi, SSC (Science) Grade 'A', Percentage '79'	Till 2008

# Skills & Abilities

- Programming Languages: C#, Java, Apple's Swift, C, C++, Objective C (Basic), Assembly.
- Web: Asp.net(C#), Html5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular JS.
- Operating Systems: Microsoft (Windows), Apple (MAC OS).
- Database: SQLServer, Firebase
- Tools: VS Code, Android Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio, XCode, Photoshop, MS Office, Matlab, TurboC++.
- Others: Phonegap Cordova, Ionic3, React Native, Typescript, Socket Programming, UML, OOP, XPath Queries, Reverse Engineering.

# Certification

> Certified in iOS mobile application development (Sylani Welfare).

# Strength

- Great time management skills.
- > A high tolerance of stress and enjoy responsibility.
- Quick learner with grasping ability